A Guide to the Records of the Chief of Staff of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1983-1994 (bulk 1990-1994)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Chief of Staff of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1983-1994 (bulk 1990-1994)
The Library of Virginia
35539
10.8 cu. ft. (24 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1990-1994: Wilder)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder on October 31, 1996.
Biographical Information
Lawrence Douglas Wilder was born in Richmond, Va., on January 17, 1931. He graduated from Virginia Union University in 1951 and afterwards was drafted into the Army, where he served in the Korean War from 1952-1953 and received a bronze star. He then attended the Howard University School of Law and graduated in 1959. Douglas Wilder was elected to the Virginia Senate in 1969 as the first African American member since Reconstruction and served in the Senate for five terms. In 1985, he was elected to the office of Lieutenant Governor as the first African American to be elected to statewide office in Virginia. L. Douglas Wilder won the election for Governor of Virginia in 1989 and served from January 13, 1990 to January 14, 1994. He was the first African American to be elected as Governor in United States.
The Executive Office is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state government. Members of the Executive Office include the Governor, Chief of Staff, Counselor to the Governor and their assistants. The Chief of Staff is the chief operating officer of state government, responsible for all aspects of service to citizens. The Chief oversees the Cabinet members and agency heads in the administration of state government and is also responsible for the operations of the Governor's Office. The Chief is assisted in these responsibilities by a Deputy Chief of Staff and an Executive Assistant.
Scope and Content
Records, 1990-1994, of the Chief of Staff during the administration of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder. The collection is housed in 24 boxes and includes correspondence, financial and budget reports, memorandum, minutes, newsletters, progress reports, publications, schedules, and other documents. The collection is arranged into three series, Series I: Correspondence and Subject Files, Series II: Secretariat Records, and Series III: Governor's General Correspondence.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series: Series I: Correspondence and Subject Files, Series II: Secretariat Records, and Series III: Governor's General Correspondence.
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence and Subject Files, 1987-1994 (bulk 1990-1994)., Extent: 3.38 cu. ft. (8 boxes). (Box 1-8)
  The Correspondence and Subject Files series is housed in 8 boxes, and is arranged into two (2) subseries. Subseries have been designated for: A. Correspondence and B. Subject Files. The series consists of correspondence, financial reports, memorandum, minutes, newsletters, programs, publications, reports, schedules, and other documents.
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1989-1993 (bulk 1992-1993)., 1.4 cu. ft. (4 boxes) (Box 1-3, 25)
    This subseries is housed in 4 boxes and includes correspondence, budgets, clippings, memorandum, and reports. The bulk of the letters were written to and from Jorman Granger, Deputy Chief of Staff, and Jay T. Shropshire, Chief of Staff, who resigned in November 1993.
    - General Correspondence, 1992 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, May-June 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, July-Aug. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, Sept.-Oct. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence, Nov.-Dec. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, Jan.-Feb. 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, Mar. 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - General Correspondence, 1993 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - General Correspondence, Apr. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, May 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, June 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, July 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence, Aug. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, Sept. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, Sept.-Oct. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, Oct. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, Nov. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, The Marshall Group LTD, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence, Dicks, John G. III "Chips," 1989 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, Jay T. Shropshire, Chief of Staff, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, Jay T. Shropshire, Clerk of Senate/Chief of Staff, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, Legislative Initiatives of the Commission on Overcrowding, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B: Subject Files, 1982-1994 (bulk 1992-1993)., 2.25 cu. ft. (5 boxes) (Box 4-8)
    This subseries is housed in 5 boxes and is arranged alphabetically by folder title. Includes administrative records, clippings, correspondence, memorandum, minutes, publications, reports, and schedules.
    Major topics incude an African trade and cultural summit, including a trip by the governor to several African countries; the Total Quality Management system; the U.S. Senate Productivity Award for Virginia, created in 1983 to honor organizations that significantly improved productivity and performance (now the U.S. Senate Productivity and Quality Award); and the Governor's Commission on Violent Crime, including numerous publications and reports on the juvenile court and youth violence. The Governor's Commission on Violet Crime was created by Governor Wilder in 1992 by Executive Order 92, and given the duty of advising the Governor on how the Commonwealth could address and reduce the frequency and impact of violent crime, including the causes of and offenders responsible and the role of firearms and firearms trafficking in violent crime.
    - African Summit Trip, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - African Trade Mission, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - African/SGA Trade and Cultural Summit, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - (Box 4)
    - Governor's Commission on Violent Crime (GCVC), Anti-Violent Crime Legislation Bill Signing Ceremony, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - GCVC Crime Commission Meetings, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - GCVC Crime Commission Studies - Legislation, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - GCVC Crime Prevention 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Governor's Commission on Violent Crime, Interim Report Working Paper, Dec. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Governor's Commission on Violent Crime, Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - GCVC Injury Prevention Plan for the Commonwealth of Virginia, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - GCVC Juvenile Justice, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - GCVC Juvenile Offender Study, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - GCVC Law Enforcement and Education Concerns in the Prevention of Violent Crime, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - GCVC Memorandum, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - GCVC Prevention of Violent Crime, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - GCVC, Proposed Speech to Governor's Commission on Violent Crime, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - GCVC, Publication: Juvenile and Family Court Journal - Juvenile Court and the Role of the Juvenile Court Judge, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - GCVC, Publication: Juvenile and Family Court Journal - The Juvenile Court and Serious Offenders, 38 Recommendations, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - GCVC, Publication: Metropolitan Court Judges Committee Report, Deprived Children, A Judicial Response, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - GCVC, Publication: National Court Appointed Special Advocate, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - GCVC, Publication: Report of the Virginia Council on Teen Pregnancy Prevention to Secretary of Health and Human Resources, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - GCVC, Publication: Virginia Council on Coordinating Prevention Comprehensive Prevention Plan for Virginia, 1992-2000 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - GCVC, Public Hearing, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - GCVC, Reference Materials, Articles, and News Clippings 1983-1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - GCVC, Remarks, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - GCVC, Report: Combating Violent Crime - 24 Recommendations to Strengthen Criminal Justice, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - GCVC, Report: Concept Paper, Safe Virginia Community Program, July 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - GCVC, Report: Cost and Cost Savings of 1992-2000 Comprehensive Plan for Virginia, May 1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - GCVC, Report: Interim Report (Draft), Dec. 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - GCVC, Report: Interm Sub-Committee Report, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - GCVC, Report: Interim Report, The Commission on Stimulating Personal Initiative to Overcome Poverty, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - GCVC, Report: Institute on Youth Aggression for School Personnel, July 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - GCVC, Report: Portrait of Violence, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - GCVC, Report: Promoting a Safe School Environment on Youth Aggression, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - GCVC, Report: Statewide Injury Prevention Committee Intentional Injuries Sub-Committee, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - GCVC, Report: The Commission on the Reduction of Sexual Assault Victimization in Virginia, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - GCVC, Report: The Third National Injury Control Conference, April 1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - GCVC, Report: To Secretary of the Public Safety on Clinton Administration Budget Proposals, March 1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - GCVC, Report: Violent Crime and Worker's Safety in Virginia's Convenience Stores, Dec. 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - GCVC, Statement of Delegate G. Steven Agee, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - GCVC, Survey of Virginia Citizens Concerning Violent Crime Issues, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - GCVC Task Force, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - GCVC, Virginia Commission on Youth Newsletter, March 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - GCVC, Virginia Crime Prevention Association, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - GCVC, Virginia Partnership for the Prevention of Youth Violence, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - GCVC, Youth and Families Violence Prevention, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - GCVC, Youth in Crisis Mobilizing the Next Generation, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - GCVC, Youth Violence Prevention Program, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Total Quality Management Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Total Quality Management Correspondence, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Total Quality Management Correspondence, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Total Quality Management Training Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Total Quality Management, Quality Council of Greater Richmond, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Senate Productivity Award for Virginia Correspondence, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Senate Productivity Award for Virginia, Process Notebook, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - U.S. Senate Productivity Award for Virginia, Quality Council of Greater Richmond, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - U.S. Senate Productivity Award for Virginia, Correspondence, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Series II: Secretariat Records, 1991-1994., Extent: 5.65 cu. ft. (13 boxes) (Box 9-21)
  The Secretariat Records series, 1991-1994, consists of 13 boxes and is arranged alphabetically by secretariat and then by folder title. The collection includes materials such as briefings, budget and financial records, correspondence, memorandum, publications, reports, weekly activity reports, and other documents.
  The office of the Secretary of Commerce and Resources, established in 1972, was responsible for the areas of economic development and natural resources; it was split into two separate offices in 1986. In 1993, the name of the Secretary of Economic Development was changed ot the Secretary of Commerce and Trade. The records from this secretariat includes weekly activity reports discussing projects of interest within the Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services and an African Summit trip. Lawrence H. Framme III served as Secretary of Economic Development from 1990-1992. Cate Magennis served as secretary from 1992-1994, during the renaming of the secretariat.
  The Secretariat of Education submitted a report on the preparation for educating the Virginia work force for the 21st century. James W. Dyke Jr served as Secretary of Education from 1990 to 1993; Karen J. Petersen served as Secretary of Education from 1993 to 1994.
  Records from the Secretary of Finance, Paul Timmreck (1990-1996), include audit reports, biennial budgets and forecast for future appropriations for the Commonwealth during the Wilder administration, as well as reports discussing compensation for the state work force. There is correspondence from Secretariat Timmreck to President Clinton regarding federal budget elimination of the Small Business Development Center that would result in adverse affect on the state small business development in Virginia. A copy of the 1993 Virginia Acts of the Assembly Chapter 994 is included with this collection. Budgetary items such as funding for capital outlay projects are discussed. Weekly reports outline the secretariat's activities and a memo outlines the secretary's various meetings and attendance outside of the office.
  The Secretary of Natural Resources, Elizabeth Haskell (1990-1994) provides background information on the implementation of the Department of Environmental Quality. The effort to clean up the Chesapeake Bay is also documented in the Chesapeake Executive Council records.
  The Secretary of Public Safety, O. Randolph Rollins (1992-1994), provides weekly reports documenting activities of the various departments within Public Safety. There is information concerning jail overcrowding and the possible construction of new prisons.
  - Secretary of Administration, Correspondence, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Administration, Correspondence 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Administration, Weekly Activity Reports 1992 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Correspondence, Aug. 1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Correspondence, Sept. 1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Correspondence, Oct. 1993 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Correspondence, Nov. 1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Dept. of Housing and Community Development, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Dept. of Mines, Minerals, and Energy, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Dept. of Minority Business Enterprise, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade, United Airlines Proposal, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Virginia Employment Commission, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Virginia Enterprise Zone Designations, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Affordable Housing Development Corporation, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Center on Rural Development, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, Feb. 1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, Mar. 1993 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, Apr. 1993 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, May 1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, June 1993 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, July 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, Oct. 1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Correspondence, Dec. 1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Dept. of Economic Development, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Dept. of Economic Development, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Dept. of Economic Development, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Dept. of Minority Business Enterprise, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Six Month Report, Dec. 1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Virginia Chamber of Commerce Economic Summit, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Weekly Activity Reports, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Weekly Activity Reports, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Weekly Activity Reports, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Secretary of Economic Development, Weekly Activity Reports, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Education, America 2000, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Education, Center for Innovative Technology, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Education, Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Education, Correspondence, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Education, Correspondence, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Education, Correspondence, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Education, Correspondence, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Education, Council of Higher Education, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Education, James Madison University, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Education, Monthly Procurement, 1988-1992 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Education, Norfolk State University, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Education, Report: Governor's Task Force on Substance Abuse and Sexual Assaults on College Campus, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Education, State Library and Archives, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Secretary of Education, University of Virginia, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Secretary of Education, VCU, 1991-1993 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Secretary of Education, Virginia Military Institute, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Secretary of Education, Virginia State University, 1991-1993 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Secretary of Education, Virginia Tech, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Secretary of Education, Virginia Union University, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Secretary of Education, Virginia Student Assistance Authorities, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Secretary of Education, William and Mary, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Secretary of Education, Workforce 2000, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Apr. 1992 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, May-June 1992 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, July-Aug. 1992 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Sept. 1992 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Oct.-Nov. 1992 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Nov. 1992 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Dec. 1992 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Jan. 1993 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Feb. 1993 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Mar. 1993 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Apr. 1993 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, with Copy of 1993 Acts of Assembly, Apr. 1993 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, May 1993 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, June 1993 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, July-Aug. 1993 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Sept.-Oct. 1993 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memos, Nov.-Dec. 1993 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Finance, Governor's Reduction in Spending Plan Budget Meeting, 10 Nov. 1993 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Finance, Governor's Reduction in Spending Plan Budget Meeting, 22 Nov. 1993 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Finance, Governor's Reduction in Spending Plan Budget Meeting, 23 Nov. 1993 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Finance, President Bush Budget Proposal, Jan. 1992 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Finance, Virginia Lottery Annual Reports, 1989-1992 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Finance, Weekly Activity Reports, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Secretary of Finance, Weekly Reports, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Secretary of Health and Human Resources, Weekly Activity Report, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources, Correspondence and Memos, Feb.-Oct. 1992 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources, Correspondence and Memos, Nov. 1992 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources, Correspondence and Memos, Jan.-Sept. 1993 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources, Chesapeake Executive Council, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources, Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources, Report: Dept. of Environmental Quality Implementation, Oct. 1992 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources, Review of Virginia's Administrative Process Act, Oct. 1992 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources, Weekly Reports, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources, Weekly Reports, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Secretary of Public Safety, Correspondence and Memos, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Secretary of Public Safety, Dept. of Corrections Briefing Book, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Secretary of Public Safety, Drug Policy, 1991-1993 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Public Safety, Report: 1989 Commission on Prison and Jail Overcrowding, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Public Safety, Weekly Report, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Correspondence and Memos, 1990-1992 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Correspondence and Memos, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Correspondence and Memos, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Correspondence and Memos, 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Correspondence and Memos, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Correspondence and Memos, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Correspondence and Memos, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Report: Dulles Corridor Rail Project, Feb. 1992 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Weekly Activity Reports, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Weekly Updates, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Series III: Governor's General Correspondence, 1990-1993., Extent: 1.35 cu. ft. (3 boxes) (Box 22-24)
  The Governor's General Correspondence, 1990-1993, consists of 3 boxes and is arranged chronologically. The collection consists of items sent to or from Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, and includes materials such as awards, clippings, correspondence, pamphlets, photographs, reports, and other documents. Notable correspondents include Bill Clinton, first as governor and then as president, George Bush, Rita Mae Brown, Al Sharpton, Edward M. Kennedy, Robert C. Byrd, Frank R. Wolf, Terry Sanford, Alan Cranston, and John Warner, among others.
  - Correspondence, Jan.-Aug. 1990 (Box 22, Folder 1)